In the last video,
在上个视频中
we trained our PCA model and applied it to our original normalized training data to
我们训练了 PCA 模型并将其应用到原始归一化训练数据上
reduce the dimensionality of that data from 34 dimensions to seven components.
使数据的维度从 34 维降到 7 个成分
Using this transformed data,
我们现在可以
we're now ready to implement k-means clustering.
利用这个转换后的数据实现 K 均值聚类了
The steps to create a k-means estimator and deploy it will look very familiar.
创建 K 均值 estimator 并部署它的步骤与之前的很相似
So I'll go over the model creation,
我将快速过一遍
training, and deployment fairly quickly.
模型创建 训练和部署步骤
Now, our first step is to define a k-means model.
第一步是定义 K 均值模型
If I click on the k-means documentation,
打开 K 均值的参考文档
I can see exactly what parameters this takes in.
看看这个函数需要哪些参数
I can see I have to import this k-means estimator and pass in
可以看出 我需要导入 KMeans estimator
a role and details about the train instance count and type,
传入角色并设定训练实例的数量以及类型
I can also see a hyper-parameter here,
这里还有个超参数
k. If I look at the documentation below,
k往下浏览文档
I can see that this is the number of clusters I want this algorithm to produce.
这个 k 表示我希望算法生成的聚类数量
In this notebook, I gave you some advice on choosing a
在 notebook 中 我提供了关于如何选择合适的 k 值的
good k. This is based on collected empirical data.
建议这些建议是根据经验数据提出的
Essentially, I gave you some information looking at how
我介绍了对于不同的 k 值
close our data points are to each cluster center for
如何查看数据点与每个聚类中心的距离
various values for k. A bad value for k would be
一种糟糕的 k 值是
one so high that only one or two very close datapoints are near it,
K 值太高了 只有 1、2 个数据点非常接近聚类中心
and another bad k would be one so small
另一种糟糕的 k 值是 k 值太小
that datapoints are really far away from the centers.
数据点距离聚类中心太远
I wrote a bit about the elbow selection method,
我还介绍了“肘部”选择方法
basically looking for a distance elbow that
即选择这样一种肘部距离
indicates that there's enough separation to distinguish the data points in
使我们能够足够区分
each cluster but also include
每个聚类中的数据点
enough clusters so that the data points aren't extremely far away from each cluster.
但是还要包含足够多的聚类 使每个数据点距离每个聚类的距离都不是太远
The elbow method takes a value for k and looks at
肘部方法接受一个 k 值
the average distance of each of your data points to the cluster centers.
然后查看每个数据点距离聚类中心的平均距离
It looks at how this value decreases as k increases,
看看当 k 增大时 这个值是如何减小的
and it says if you see an elbow or a place
如果看到像胳膊肘一样的形状或位置
where this stops decreasing and at a significant rate,
此时这个值不再显著下降
then you should choose that k. I tried out some code for various values of k,
那么就应该选择这个 k 值我尝试了各种 k 值的代码
and I think 8 is probably a good number of clusters to use here.
发现对我们来说 8 是比较合适的聚类数量
We can see that the average distance is decreasing up until about this point.
可以看到 在此点之前 平均距离一直在下降
Okay. So when I defined a k-means estimator I passed in a role,
Ok在定义 k 均值 estimator 时 我传入了角色
details about the instance type,
指定了实例类型
and output path which I'm just using the same one that I used for
以及输出路径 与之前 PCA 模型使用的路径一样
our PCA model and a number of clusters which I've specified to be 8.
然后将聚类数量设为 8
After creating this model,
创建此模型后
and I'm calling it k-means,
我称为 kmeans
this now expects to be trained on a particular kind of formatted training data.
下面使用特殊格式的训练数据训练该模型
These are the same steps we took to train our PCA model.
这些步骤与训练 PCA 模型的一样
I'm taking our counties_transformed dataframe,
传入 counties_transformed dataframe
and I'm converting it into a NumPy array of float values.
将其转换为浮点值 NumPy 数组
Then I'm calling kmeans.record_set,
然后调用 kmeans.record_set
passing in this NumPy data,
传入这个 NumPy 数据
and this returns record set formatted data.
返回记录集格式的数据
Then I can call fit, passing in
然后调用 fit()
this formatted data and creating a training job with this name.
传入这个格式化数据并创建一个训练作业 作业名称是这个
This is something you'll be able to refer to later
之后 如果你想查看模型属性
if you want to take a look at the model attributes.
可以引用这个名称
After the training job completed,
训练作业运行完毕后
I then deploy this model and created a k-means predictor.
然后部署此模型并创建 k 均值预测器
Again, I'm using the same arguments as for our PCA model,
使用的参数与 PCA 模型的一样
and they can see that a k-means model and endpoint were created here.
可以看到 在这里创建了 k 均值模型和端点
Then I can use this predictor to generate cluster labels for all of our data points.
然后使用此预测器为所有数据点生成聚类标签
Here, I'm getting that predictor by name and calling predict.
在这里通过名称获取该预测器并调用 predict()
Then I want to get our Numpy formatted data and pass it into our predictor.
然后将格式化的 NumPy 数据传入预测器中
So this predictor should take in our component training data,
这个预测器将接受成分训练数据
and return some information about the clusters.
并返回关于聚类的信息
In this next cell, I'm going to print out what
在下个单元格中
that cluster info is for our first data point,
输出第一个数据点（列表中的第一个郡县）的
the first county in our list.
聚类信息
So for our county, Alabama-Autauga,
对于 Alabama-Autauga 县
I can see that its closest cluster is cluster number 3,
它最靠近聚类 3
and we also have the Euclidean distance to that cluster.
并且可以查看它与该聚类的欧几里得距离
Now, each of our data points is in seven-dimensional components space.
每个数据点都是一个 7 维成分空间
When we talk about distance to a cluster,
我们所说的到聚类的距离
we're actually looking at distance in seven dimensions
是指在 7 维空间里
between our data point and the center of its closest cluster.
数据点与它最靠近的聚类的中心之间的距离
In the next few cells, I'm going to do
在下面的几个单元格中
some quick visualization and look at how many of our data points fall into each cluster.
我将可视化数据并查看每个聚类有多少个数据点
So here, I'm looking at the label closest_cluster,
在这里查看标签 closest_cluster
and I expect this to be a value like 3.
预计值为 3
I'm getting that cluster label for each point in
我将获取 cluster_info 中每个数据点的聚类标签
our cluster info and storing it as cluster labels.
并存储为 cluster_labels
Then I'm going to count up how many of our data points fall into each cluster,
然后看看有多少数据点落入每个聚类中
and I'll print out those counts.
并输出这些计数
So these are in order from basically most popular at least,
这些值按照落入的数据点最多到最少排序
and I can see that most of our data points fall into cluster number 1.
大部分数据都落入了聚类 1 里
It's important to note that these are also indexed by 0,
注意 它们从 0 开始设定索引
so there's a cluster 0 up to a cluster 7.
所以从聚类 0 到聚类 7
Here's just another way to visualize these counts,
这是另一种可视化这些计数的方式
which is just displaying them as a histogram.
即显示为直方图
If I see that my data is wildly unevenly clustered here,
如果数据聚类很不均匀
it may be an indicator that my choice of k was not a great separator for the data.
那么表明所选的 k 值可能不适合区分数据
But this looks fairly evenly distributed among clusters.
但是这个图看起来分布比较均匀
Now, I've stored all my cluster labels,
我存储了所有的聚类标签
and I'm actually done with the model endpoint,
并且模型端点使用完毕了
so as a last step here,
最后一步
I'm going to delete my k-means predictor endpoint.
删除 k 均值预测器端点
Next, I'll challenge you to extract the trained model
接下来 请你提取训练过的模型的属性
attributes so you can look at the data and cluster centroids.
从而查看数据和聚类形心
I've also included some visualization code.
我还提供了一些可视化代码
The best part of this is really getting to learn something about
最重要的是真正地了解这些数据
this data and show how counties are naturally grouped together.
看看郡县是如何自然分组的
So next, try to do this on your own,
请自己完成这个任务
and if you'd like, you can consult my solution.
遇到问题也可以参考我的答案